A Guide to the Records of the Virginia George Washington Bicentennial Commission, 1932
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia George Washington Bicentennial Commission 1932
The Library of Virginia
31629
.81 cu. ft (2 boxes) and 1 volume
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred 1934.
Historical Information
The Virginia George Washington Bicentennial Commission was created by the General Assembly in 1926. The Commission planned and coordinated a program of celebration activities throughout Virginia during 1932, the two hundred anniversary of the birth of George Washington. In 1930, the General Assembly amended the act by increasing the membership of the commission from six to eleven members, including the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, the Clerk of the House of Delegates, 3 members appointed from the House of Delegates and 3 members appointed from the Senate. The commission ceased operation on 31 December 1932. A final report was submitted to the General Assembly in January 1934.
Scope and Content
Collection contains records of the George Washington Bicentennial Commission and includes correspondence, reports, news clippings, questionnaires, programs, photographs, and sheet music. Of particular interest are reports from various localities detailing commemorative events held during 1932.
Collection also includes a document related to the Virginia Homecoming Commission which includes the text of the proclamation of Governor John Garland Pollard establishing the Homecoming Commission, excerpts of minutes, and other materials related to the Homecoming Commission.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by folder title
Contents List
- Article: "George Washington Bicentennial Tree Planting" by Charles Lathrop Pack, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pollard, John Garland, Jr.: "The George Washington Bicentennial Commission in Virginia", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pollard, John Garland: Homecoming Proclamation and Virginia Homecoming Commission, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Program: "Official Celebration of the 200th Anniversary of the Birth of George Washington and in Honor of the Governors attending the Governors' Conference", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Publication: "Celebration by the General Assembly of Virginia in Commemoration of the 200th Anniversary of the Birth of George Washington", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Report of Activities, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Reports from Localities: Alexandria - Montgomery County, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Reports from Localities: Norfolk - Wytheville, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sheet Music with Lyrics and Script: "Washington at Mount Vernon" by Florence Wickham, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Reports from Localities: Mineral (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sheet Music: "Washington at Mount Vernon" by Florence Wickham, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)